HASIDUL ISLAM

Phone: $+8801624142227 \diamond$ Email: ihasidul@gmail.com \diamond github.com/ihasidul \diamond linkedin.com/in/ihasidul \diamond Stackoverflow: Hasidul Islam

ABOUT ME

I am a software engineer with more than 2 years of experience, specializing in Python development and DevOps. I have a strong background in developing back-ends as well as setting up CI/CD pipelines with tools like Bitbucket Pipeline and project deployment. I am passionate about open-source contributions and have actively participated in open-source projects. I am always eager to learn and stay up-to-date with the latest industry trends and technologies.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Mevrik

August, 2023 - Present

Software Engineer

- · Build microservices in Python using technologies like **Django REST Framework**, **FastAPI**, **Post-gres**, **Redis**, **Elasticsearch**, **Graylog**, **Datadog and MongoDB**.
- · Build tools for better digital customer experience for Enterprise and SAAS customers.

Medina Tech Ltd.

July, 2022 - July, 2023

Software Engineer(Level 2)

- · Built back-ends in Python using **Django REST Framework and Postgres**.
- · Implemented CI/CD pipeline using **Bitbucket** Pipeline. I also setup and maintained **AWS EC2** for **Django**, **Node**, **React** projects using tools like **wsgi**, **pm2**, **apache**.
- · Worked with international clients from Dubai and Germany.
- · Wrote web scrapers using Python libraries like **beautifulsoup** and **scrapy** for data collection.

Medina Tech Ltd.

August, 2021 - June, 2022

Software Engineer(Level 1)

- · Developed and maintained back-ends built using **Django**, **Django REST Framework**, **PostgreSQL**, **Flask**, **apache**.
- · Got Employ of The Quarter for best performance.

Medina Tech Ltd.

June, 2021 - August, 2021

Software Engineer Intern

- · Integrated a Flask(Python) chatbot to Symfony(PHP) web app.
- · Wrote automation scripts to automate English to Bangla translation for in-house software and websites, saving project development time.
- · Internship experience interview.

EDUCATION

American International University-Bangladesh (AIUB)

2017 - 2021

BSc in Computer Science and Engineering

GPA: 3.90/4.00

Dhaka City College

2014 - 2016

Higher Secondary Certificate(HSC)

GPA: 5.00/5.0

Fulgazi Model Pilot High School

Secondary School Certificate(SSC)

GPA: 5.00/5.00

PROJECTS

Dr.Chashi

Python, Django, Django REST Framework, Postgre

Dr. Chashi is a Digital Farming solution that enables farmers and agro stakeholders to access accurate farming knowledge and manage their farming needs. I developed the Python backend for this project, deployed it on AWS EC2, and created an internal validation tool to assess the ML component's detection accuracy. Dr. Chashi has also received government funding, highlighting its significance and potential impact in the agricultural domain.

Project Website:Dr.Chashi

slurp

Python, Scrapy, CircleCI, Markdown

This is an open-source project of a knowledge-based website. I wrote Scrapper using **Scrapy(a webcrawling framework written in Python)** for this project. Also wrote some **CircleCI** configuration for my script. Fixed documentation is written in Markdown. I also review code for this project.

Live Project: slurp Github: slurp

Django Starter Project

Django, Django REST Framework, Postgre

This is a project structure for building Django-based applications using Django REST Framework and Postgres with a customized exception handler and some custom commands.

Github: Django Starter Project

Content Rating System

PHP, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, MySQL

The Content Rating System is a website where the content creator can upload their content's profile to be rated. Normal users and critics rate the content. Normal users and critics can also comment on the content.

Github: Content Rating System

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages	Python, C#, PHP
Web Technologies	HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and JavaScript
Frameworks	Django, Django REST Framework, Flask, FastAPI
Databases	MySQL, PostgreSQL, Sqlite, MongoDB and Redis
Software & Tools	Git, Linux, Bash, Markdown, Vim, VS Code, Graylog, Jira
	Pre-Commit,
DevOps Tools	Bitbucket Pipeline, AWS, EC2, RDS, pm2, Apache, Ansible

LANGUAGES

Bengali Native proficiency

English Full professional proficiency

Language proficiency test IELTS: 7.5 (Listening: 8.5, Reading: 7.0, Writing: 6.0, Speaking: 7.5)